<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Numerics on Enrico Martello</title>
    <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/tags/numerics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Numerics on Enrico Martello</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 12:14:40 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://enricomartello.github.io/tags/numerics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Grassmannization of the 3D Ising Model</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/paper_grassmannization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/paper_grassmannization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The application of Feynman’s diagrammatic technique to classical link models with local constraints seems impossible due to (i) the absence of a free Gaussian theory on top of which the perturbative expansion can be constructed, and (ii) Dyson’s collapse argument, rendering the perturbative expansion divergent. However, we show for the classical 3D Ising model how both problems can be circumvented using a Grassmann representation. This makes it possible to obtain an expansion of the spin correlation function and the magnetic susceptibility in terms of the inverse temperature in the thermodynamic limit, through which the values for the critical temperature and critical index are evaluated within 1.6% and 5.4% of their accepted values, respectively. Our work is a straightforward adaptation of the theory previously developed in an earlier paper.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring hybrid organic-metallic Perovskite thin films deposition for High-Efficiency Solar Cells through Numerical Simulations</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_eurosime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_eurosime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I presented the results of my semester-long experience at the CNR at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurosime.org&#34;&gt;25th EuroSimE&lt;/a&gt;, a conference mainly involved in simulations and experiments for microelectronics and microsystems. The focus of this work was on simulating the deposition of a metal-organic perovskite on a substrate, in order to understand the role of the many experimental parameters involved in the innovative deposition technique described &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1039/D1TA02535J&#34;&gt;in this work&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Although we did not manage to present a paper, but the poster won the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurosime.org/index.php/awards/&#34;&gt;Outstanding poster award&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;, by participants&amp;rsquo; vote.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;As it is a large file, it might take some time to download it - be patient :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the Adiabatic non-Hermitian Berry Phase in Feedback-Coupled Harmonic Oscillators</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_warwick22/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_warwick22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the first time since I began my PhD, I was able to spend more time traveling for conferences. In particular, I presented this poster at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/sci/physics/research/theory/events/iop2022/&#34;&gt;Theory of Condensed Matter (TCM) Meeting&lt;/a&gt;, at the University of Warwick, then a few weeks later I took part to the conference on &lt;a href=&#34;http://cmqm2022.iopconfs.org/home&#34;&gt;Condensed Matter and Quantum Materials (CMQM)&lt;/a&gt; organised by the Institute of Physics (IoP) at the University of Bath, and finally I have presented it at the University of Strathclyde, Glasgow, for the conference on &lt;a href=&#34;https://desoeq.phys.strath.ac.uk/desoeqqsum22/&#34;&gt;Designing Out of Eequilibrium many-body Quantum systems (DesOEQ)&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;For more details about this work, &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2205.02700&#34;&gt;take a look at the paper&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;As it is a large file, it might take some time to download it - be patient :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic Mechanical Metamaterials for non-Hermitian Hamiltonians </title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_warwick21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_warwick21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I presented this poster at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/sci/physics/research/theory/events/iop2021/&#34;&gt;Theory of Condensed Matter (TCM) Meeting&lt;/a&gt;, held in Warwick. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;For more details about this work, &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2107.09649&#34;&gt;take a look at the paper&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;As it is a large file, it might take some time to download it - be patient :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grassmannization of the 3D Ising Model</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_warwick19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_warwick19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From 17th to 20th of September, right before I graduated my MSc, I had the chance to take part (and help managing, together with other MSc students) the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iqis2018.imm.cnr.it/&#34;&gt;11th Italian Quantum Information Science Conference (IQIS)&lt;/a&gt; organised in Catania. Here I presented the work I had carried out during my Erasmus as part of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theorie.physik.uni-muenchen.de/lsschollwoeck/members/professors/pollet/&#34;&gt;Lode Pollet&amp;rsquo;s group&lt;/a&gt;. At the time I presented a different version of the poster. The one you find here is a &amp;ldquo;more standalone&amp;rdquo; version, that I presented at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/sci/physics/research/theory/events/iop2019/&#34;&gt;Theory of Condensed Matter (TCM) Meeting&lt;/a&gt;, held in Warwick. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;For more details about this work, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/2504-3900/12/1/20&#34;&gt;take a look at the paper&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;As it is a large file, it might take some time to download it - be patient :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
