<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Enrico Martello</title>
    <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Enrico Martello</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 18:56:13 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://enricomartello.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the adiabatic Non-Hermitian Berry Phase in Feedback-Coupled Oscillators</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/unict_seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/unict_seminar/</guid>
      <description>In this talk I presented our most recent work at the University of Catania. It was the first time I ever presented my work!
We measured for the first time the Berry phase in the case of a non-Hermitian Hamiltonian using a mechanical metamaterial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian Deployment Triggers</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/contributions/deploy-triggers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/contributions/deploy-triggers/</guid>
      <description>Addressed pretty significant page load performance issue founde in larger deployments. Eliminates uses of intensive backend query, replacing it with an asynchronous API call against a lucene index. This change reduces page load from from 2+ minutes to nearly instant, with an incredibly responsive UI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demo of Graide: AI Powered Assistive Grading Engine</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/6bit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/6bit/</guid>
      <description>I have been helping people at 6bit testing and adding new features to Graide, a platform that reduces grading workload while increasing the quality of feedback to be given to students. Check how it works!
I have been demo-ing at L@S2022 where the issues related to teaching and learning at scale have been discussed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grassmannization of the 3D Ising Model</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/grassmannization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/grassmannization/</guid>
      <description>The application of Feynman’s diagrammatic technique to classical link models with local constraints seems impossible due to (i) the absence of a free Gaussian theory on top of which the perturbative expansion can be constructed, and (ii) Dyson’s collapse argument, rendering the perturbative expansion divergent. However, we show for the classical 3D Ising model how both problems can be circumvented using a Grassmann representation. This makes it possible to obtain an expansion of the spin correlation function and the magnetic susceptibility in terms of the inverse temperature in the thermodynamic limit, through which the values for the critical temperature and critical index are evaluated within 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Added Docker Build Status Badge to shields.io</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/contributions/shields-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 17:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/contributions/shields-docker/</guid>
      <description>Shields.io is a massive library of badges that can be inserted into project README&amp;rsquo;s or websites displaying various statuses (code coverage, health, version, etc). Support for docker was missing the current build health, and was a pretty trivial addition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schema.org Structured Data documentation fixes</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/contributions/schema-org/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 17:08:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/contributions/schema-org/</guid>
      <description>While adding Structured Data to a client&amp;rsquo;s website I found some example JSON that was invalid. Simple contribution to cleanup the user documentation providing syntactically valid JSON documents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BOSH release for Bamboo &amp; Remote Agents</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/creations/bosh-agents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/creations/bosh-agents/</guid>
      <description>BOSH (Bosh Outer SHell) &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip; is an open source tool for release engineering, deployment, lifecycle management, and monitoring of distributed systems.&amp;rdquo; And it&amp;rsquo;s amazingly powerful. This examples uses BOSH to provision an Alassian vendor app running on JDK along with the support Postgres database and agents to support it. The releases manages the health of services and will automatically provision, start/stop processes across the various services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forcing Visits to use SSL</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/blog/force-ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 14:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/blog/force-ssl/</guid>
      <description>Intro Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether it&amp;rsquo;s a CakePHP app for a client, your own personal CMS, or any other web based application. If your passing around passwords or other sensitive info you should really implement SSL. SSL provides 2 main perks to your visitors.
First it encrypts all communication that flies across the web. This prevents curious or devious billies from getting your secrets. Secondly it ensures to the user that your server is in fact who it claims, and not a nasty &amp;lsquo;man in the middle&amp;quot; attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian Marketplace Plugins</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/creations/marketplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/creations/marketplace/</guid>
      <description>Multiple plugins used by thousands of teams that provide enhanced functionality of Atlassian’s core products (primarily JIRA and Bamboo) to enrich CI/CD capabilities, DevOps automation, or productivity. Functionality spans user interface, web services and persistence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker image for Bitbucket CI/CD Pipelines  &#34;shipit&#34;</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/creations/docker-marketplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/creations/docker-marketplace/</guid>
      <description>Provides required dependencies and additional utilities to simplify and codify the process of building, testing and delivering Atlassian plugins all the way to the live marketplace. Executes integration/AUT level tests against all stated compatible versions for the productUploads generated artifact to Atlassian marketplaceProvides corresponding metadata indicating version, release notes, and compatibility</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Results</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/search/</guid>
      <description>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related search layout template.
No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html
Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.
This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js
Initial setup Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml
[outputs] home = [&amp;#34;HTML&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;JSON&amp;#34;] Searching additional fileds To search additional fields defined in front matter, you must add it in 2 places.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
