<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Enrico Martello</title>
    <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Enrico Martello</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 12:14:40 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://enricomartello.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>De Sidus for Feltrinelli</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/contributions/talk_feltrinelli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/contributions/talk_feltrinelli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As one of the active members of De sidus association I was invited to discuss the relation between man and time, and how has the concept of time evolved both on physical ground and in terms of the understanding we have of our world! &lt;br&gt;&#xA;Together with one of De Sidus member, we discussed at one of the Feltrinelli stores in Catania. Check &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/reel/C4vwZoRoq55/?utm_source=ig_web_copy_link&amp;amp;igsh=MzRlODBiNWFlZA==&#34;&gt;our video&lt;/a&gt; (Italian only, sorry about it)!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- [&lt;img src=&#34;https://enricomartello.github.io/img/eps_smt.jpeg&#34; width=&#34;60%&#34; /&gt;](/img/eps_smt.jpeg) --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DNA divers Catania</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/contributions/dna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/contributions/dna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am also a proud member of &lt;a href=&#34;https://dnadivingcatania.it&#34;&gt;DNA Divers Catania&lt;/a&gt;, based on the shores of the stunning &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.isoleciclopi.it&#34;&gt;marine protected area &amp;ldquo;Isole Ciclopi&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. Our mission is to spread a love for nature and help people appreciate the beauty beneath the sea&amp;rsquo;s surface, whether through snorkeling or scuba diving!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- [&lt;img src=&#34;https://enricomartello.github.io/img/eps_smt.jpeg&#34; width=&#34;60%&#34; /&gt;](/img/eps_smt.jpeg) --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EPS Young Minds Catania</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/contributions/eps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/contributions/eps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I collaborated with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/epsyoungmindscatania/&#34;&gt;EPS Young Minds section Catania&lt;/a&gt; in their project involving High School students and Arduino. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;The goal of the project was to build a network of sensors able to track down pollution levels in different areas of the city, in order to sensitize young people awareness of the problem of pollution, teach them how do sensors work and how do tracking and measuring work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://enricomartello.github.io/img/eps_smt.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://enricomartello.github.io/img/eps_smt.jpeg&#34; width=&#34;60%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the Adiabatic Non-Hermitian Berry Phase in Feedback-Coupled Oscillators</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/paper_measuring/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/paper_measuring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this work we verify experimentally that the adiabatic non-Hermitian Berry phase is a purely geometrical effect that leads to significant amplification and damping of the amplitude also for non-cyclical paths within the parameter space even when all eigenenergies are real. We further observe a non-Hermitian analog of the Aharonov&amp;ndash;Bohm solenoid effect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic Mechanical Lattices with Synthetic Interactions</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/paper_synthetic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/paper_synthetic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We experimentally engineer synthetic lattice Hamiltonians in our mechanical system, with control over local site energies and loss and gain as well as control over the complex hopping between oscillators. Beyond linear terms, we experimentally demonstrate how this measurement-based feedback approach opens the window to independently introducing nonlinear interaction terms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coexistence of stable and unstable population dynamics in a nonlinear non-Hermitian mechanical dimer</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/paper_coexistence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/paper_coexistence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We experimentally and theoretically investigate the dynamics of Hatano-Nelson model on two sites (dimer), and then we make the non-reciprocal hoppings depend on the population imbalance between the two sites, thus introducing the non-Hermiticity in a dynamical manner. In the latter case we find that we can tune from stable to unstable population dynamics by simply changing the initial phase difference between the two sites.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grassmannization of the 3D Ising Model</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/paper_grassmannization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/paper_grassmannization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The application of Feynman’s diagrammatic technique to classical link models with local constraints seems impossible due to (i) the absence of a free Gaussian theory on top of which the perturbative expansion can be constructed, and (ii) Dyson’s collapse argument, rendering the perturbative expansion divergent. However, we show for the classical 3D Ising model how both problems can be circumvented using a Grassmann representation. This makes it possible to obtain an expansion of the spin correlation function and the magnetic susceptibility in terms of the inverse temperature in the thermodynamic limit, through which the values for the critical temperature and critical index are evaluated within 1.6% and 5.4% of their accepted values, respectively. Our work is a straightforward adaptation of the theory previously developed in an earlier paper.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the adiabatic Non-Hermitian Berry Phase in Feedback-Coupled Oscillators</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/unict_seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/unict_seminar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this talk I presented our most recent work at the University of Catania. It was the first time I ever presented my work!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We measured for the first time the Berry phase in the case of a non-Hermitian Hamiltonian using a mechanical metamaterial.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demo of Graide: AI Powered Assistive Grading Engine</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/6bit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/6bit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been helping people at 6bit by testing and adding new features to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.graide.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Graide&lt;/a&gt;, a platform that reduces grading workload while increasing the quality of feedback given to students. Take a look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z9nVtXLrrZM&amp;amp;ab_channel=Graide-TheAssessment%26FeedbackPlatform&#34;&gt;how it works&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have been demo-ing at &lt;a href=&#34;https://learningatscale.acm.org/las2022/&#34;&gt;L@S2022&lt;/a&gt; where the issues related to teaching and learning at scale have been discussed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring hybrid organic-metallic Perovskite thin films deposition for High-Efficiency Solar Cells through Numerical Simulations</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_eurosime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_eurosime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I presented the results of my semester-long experience at the CNR at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurosime.org&#34;&gt;25th EuroSimE&lt;/a&gt;, a conference mainly involved in simulations and experiments for microelectronics and microsystems. The focus of this work was on simulating the deposition of a metal-organic perovskite on a substrate, in order to understand the role of the many experimental parameters involved in the innovative deposition technique described &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1039/D1TA02535J&#34;&gt;in this work&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Although we did not manage to present a paper, but the poster won the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurosime.org/index.php/awards/&#34;&gt;Outstanding poster award&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;, by participants&amp;rsquo; vote.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;As it is a large file, it might take some time to download it - be patient :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the Adiabatic non-Hermitian Berry Phase in Feedback-Coupled Harmonic Oscillators</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_warwick22/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_warwick22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the first time since I began my PhD, I was able to spend more time traveling for conferences. In particular, I presented this poster at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/sci/physics/research/theory/events/iop2022/&#34;&gt;Theory of Condensed Matter (TCM) Meeting&lt;/a&gt;, at the University of Warwick, then a few weeks later I took part to the conference on &lt;a href=&#34;http://cmqm2022.iopconfs.org/home&#34;&gt;Condensed Matter and Quantum Materials (CMQM)&lt;/a&gt; organised by the Institute of Physics (IoP) at the University of Bath, and finally I have presented it at the University of Strathclyde, Glasgow, for the conference on &lt;a href=&#34;https://desoeq.phys.strath.ac.uk/desoeqqsum22/&#34;&gt;Designing Out of Eequilibrium many-body Quantum systems (DesOEQ)&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;For more details about this work, &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2205.02700&#34;&gt;take a look at the paper&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;As it is a large file, it might take some time to download it - be patient :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data2map</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/creations/data2map/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/creations/data2map/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My father one day asked me &lt;em&gt;how could I plot lighting in an office or noise in a working environment as a heatmap on top of a floormap?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;&#xA;My first answer was something that sounds like &lt;em&gt;I can easily write down a python script that does that for you.&lt;/em&gt; It was not easy! &lt;br&gt;&#xA;It took me some days to figure out the best way to do it, and probably my approach is not the best, but it does the job! My first project that started from zero, and solves a &lt;strong&gt;real-life&lt;/strong&gt; problem: this software takes the data written in an Excel file, and then plots it on a floor-map. Check it out for more details!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic Mechanical Metamaterials for non-Hermitian Hamiltonians </title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_warwick21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_warwick21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I presented this poster at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/sci/physics/research/theory/events/iop2021/&#34;&gt;Theory of Condensed Matter (TCM) Meeting&lt;/a&gt;, held in Warwick. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;For more details about this work, &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2107.09649&#34;&gt;take a look at the paper&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;As it is a large file, it might take some time to download it - be patient :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grassmannization of the 3D Ising Model</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_warwick19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_warwick19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From 17th to 20th of September, right before I graduated my MSc, I had the chance to take part (and help managing, together with other MSc students) the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iqis2018.imm.cnr.it/&#34;&gt;11th Italian Quantum Information Science Conference (IQIS)&lt;/a&gt; organised in Catania. Here I presented the work I had carried out during my Erasmus as part of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theorie.physik.uni-muenchen.de/lsschollwoeck/members/professors/pollet/&#34;&gt;Lode Pollet&amp;rsquo;s group&lt;/a&gt;. At the time I presented a different version of the poster. The one you find here is a &amp;ldquo;more standalone&amp;rdquo; version, that I presented at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/sci/physics/research/theory/events/iop2019/&#34;&gt;Theory of Condensed Matter (TCM) Meeting&lt;/a&gt;, held in Warwick. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;For more details about this work, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/2504-3900/12/1/20&#34;&gt;take a look at the paper&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;As it is a large file, it might take some time to download it - be patient :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whale recognition</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/creations/ml_whale/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/creations/ml_whale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was the final exam of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/sci/physics/mpags/modules/comp/machinelearning/&#34;&gt;MPAGS Machine Learning course&lt;/a&gt; (access the 2021-2022 course pages to see the statement of my assessment being submitted - and passed). I was inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/c/happy-whale-and-dolphin/data&#34;&gt;this Kaggle competition&lt;/a&gt;, and I decided to try and create a Machine Learning algorithm capable of identifying marine mammals just by a picture of the dorsal fin. Since I am a beginner (or at least I was at the time), I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/datasets/bdsaglam/happy-whale-512?select=sample_submission.csv&#34;&gt;this dataset&lt;/a&gt;, that consists of the already resized and rotated images of the original dataset (hence it is supposedly easier to work with it).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2022</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/creations/aoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/creations/aoc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just by chance, a couple of years ago I came across the &lt;a href=&#34;https://adventofcode.com&#34;&gt;Advent of Code&lt;/a&gt;, and interesting project that I personally recommend to those who want to challenge themselves in doing some code-related problem solving, or who want to test/improve their knowledge of a given programming language. This year I wanted to deepen my knowledge of C++, hence the poor quality of my code. I will improve for sure!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://enricomartello.github.io/img/aoc22.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://enricomartello.github.io/img/aoc22.jpeg&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forcing Visits to use SSL</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/blog/force-ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 14:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/blog/force-ssl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether it&amp;rsquo;s a CakePHP app for a client, your own personal CMS, or any other web based application. &lt;strong&gt;If your passing around passwords or other sensitive info you should really implement SSL.&lt;/strong&gt; SSL provides 2 main perks to your visitors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First it encrypts all communication that flies across the web. This prevents curious or devious billies from getting your secrets.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Secondly it ensures to the user that your server is in fact who it claims, and not a nasty &amp;lsquo;man in the middle&amp;quot; attack.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally it gives your site that touch of class&amp;hellip;. which of course a classy person like yourself relies on.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once you implement SSL certificates on your server you&amp;rsquo;ll want to &lt;strong&gt;require secure connections&lt;/strong&gt; using Apache&amp;rsquo;s rewrite module. Now I won&amp;rsquo;t dwell on the creation and signing of certificates, its already well documented.  If your just starting out though,heres a few links I recommend;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Search Results</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/search/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related &lt;code&gt;search&lt;/code&gt; layout template.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;initial-setup&#34;&gt;Initial setup&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Search  depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;[outputs]&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  home = [&amp;#34;HTML&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;JSON&amp;#34;]&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;searching-additional-fileds&#34;&gt;Searching additional fileds&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To search additional fields defined in front matter, you must add it in 2 places.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
