<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Enrico Martello</title>
    <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Enrico Martello</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 10:23:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://enricomartello.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Demo of Graide: AI Powered Assistive Grading Engine</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/6bit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/6bit/</guid>
      <description>I have been helping people at 6bit by testing and adding new features to Graide, a platform that reduces grading workload while increasing the quality of feedback given to students. Take a look at how it works!
I have been demo-ing at L@S2022 where the issues related to teaching and learning at scale have been discussed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the adiabatic Non-Hermitian Berry Phase in Feedback-Coupled Oscillators</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/unict_seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/unict_seminar/</guid>
      <description>In this talk I presented our most recent work at the University of Catania. It was the first time I ever presented my work!
We measured for the first time the Berry phase in the case of a non-Hermitian Hamiltonian using a mechanical metamaterial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grassmannization of the 3D Ising Model</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/grassmannization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/grassmannization/</guid>
      <description>The application of Feynman’s diagrammatic technique to classical link models with local constraints seems impossible due to (i) the absence of a free Gaussian theory on top of which the perturbative expansion can be constructed, and (ii) Dyson’s collapse argument, rendering the perturbative expansion divergent. However, we show for the classical 3D Ising model how both problems can be circumvented using a Grassmann representation. This makes it possible to obtain an expansion of the spin correlation function and the magnetic susceptibility in terms of the inverse temperature in the thermodynamic limit, through which the values for the critical temperature and critical index are evaluated within 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whale recognition</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/creations/ml_whale/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/creations/ml_whale/</guid>
      <description>This was the final exam of the MPAGS Machine Learning course (access the 2021-2022 course pages to see the statement of my assessment being submitted and passed). I was inspired by this Kaggle competition, and I decided to try and create a Machine Learning algorithm capable of identifying marine mammals just by a picture of the dorsal fin. Since I am a beginner (or at least I was at the time), I used this dataset, that consists of the already resized and rotated images of the original dataset (hence it is supposedly easier to work with it).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data2map</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/creations/data2map/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/projects/creations/data2map/</guid>
      <description>My father one day asked me how could I plot lighting in an office or noise in a working environment as a heatmap on top of a floormap? My first answer was something that sounds like I can easily write down a python script that does that for you. It was not easy! It took me some days to figure out the best way to do it, and probably my approach is not the best, but it does the job!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forcing Visits to use SSL</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/blog/force-ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 14:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/blog/force-ssl/</guid>
      <description>Intro Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether it&amp;rsquo;s a CakePHP app for a client, your own personal CMS, or any other web based application. If your passing around passwords or other sensitive info you should really implement SSL. SSL provides 2 main perks to your visitors.
First it encrypts all communication that flies across the web. This prevents curious or devious billies from getting your secrets. Secondly it ensures to the user that your server is in fact who it claims, and not a nasty &amp;lsquo;man in the middle&amp;quot; attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Results</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/search/</guid>
      <description>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related search layout template.
No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html
Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.
This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js
Initial setup Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml
[outputs] home = [&amp;#34;HTML&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;JSON&amp;#34;] Searching additional fileds To search additional fields defined in front matter, you must add it in 2 places.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
