<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ising Model on Enrico Martello</title>
    <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/tags/ising-model/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ising Model on Enrico Martello</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 16:58:59 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://enricomartello.github.io/tags/ising-model/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Grassmannization of the 3D Ising Model</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/paper_grassmannization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/paper_grassmannization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The application of Feynman’s diagrammatic technique to classical link models with local constraints seems impossible due to (i) the absence of a free Gaussian theory on top of which the perturbative expansion can be constructed, and (ii) Dyson’s collapse argument, rendering the perturbative expansion divergent. However, we show for the classical 3D Ising model how both problems can be circumvented using a Grassmann representation. This makes it possible to obtain an expansion of the spin correlation function and the magnetic susceptibility in terms of the inverse temperature in the thermodynamic limit, through which the values for the critical temperature and critical index are evaluated within 1.6% and 5.4% of their accepted values, respectively. Our work is a straightforward adaptation of the theory previously developed in an earlier paper.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grassmannization of the 3D Ising Model</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_warwick19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_warwick19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From 17th to 20th of September, right before I graduated my MSc, I had the chance to take part (and help managing, together with other MSc students) the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iqis2018.imm.cnr.it/&#34;&gt;11th Italian Quantum Information Science Conference (IQIS)&lt;/a&gt; organised in Catania. Here I presented the work I had carried out during my Erasmus as part of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theorie.physik.uni-muenchen.de/lsschollwoeck/members/professors/pollet/&#34;&gt;Lode Pollet&amp;rsquo;s group&lt;/a&gt;. At the time I presented a different version of the poster. The one you find here is a &amp;ldquo;more standalone&amp;rdquo; version, that I presented at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/sci/physics/research/theory/events/iop2019/&#34;&gt;Theory of Condensed Matter (TCM) Meeting&lt;/a&gt;, held in Warwick. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;For more details about this work, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/2504-3900/12/1/20&#34;&gt;take a look at the paper&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;As it is a large file, it might take some time to download it - be patient :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
