<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latex on Enrico Martello</title>
    <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/tags/latex/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Latex on Enrico Martello</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://enricomartello.github.io/tags/latex/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the Adiabatic non-Hermitian Berry Phase in Feedback-Coupled Harmonic Oscillators</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_warwick22/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_warwick22/</guid>
      <description>For the first time since I began my PhD, I was able to spend more time traveling for conferences. In particular, I presented this poster at the Theory of Condensed Matter (TCM) Meeting, at the University of Warwick, then a few weeks later I took part to the conference on Condensed Matter and Quantum Materials (CMQM) organised by the Institute of Physics (IoP) at the University of Bath, and finally I have presented it at the University of Strathclyde, Glasgow, for the conference on Designing Out of Eequilibrium many-body Quantum systems (DesOEQ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic Mechanical Metamaterials for non-Hermitian Hamiltonians </title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_warwick21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_warwick21/</guid>
      <description>I presented this poster at the Theory of Condensed Matter (TCM) Meeting, held in Warwick. For more details about this work, take a look at the paper. As it is a large file, it might take some time to download it - be patient :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grassmannization of the 3D Ising Model</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_warwick19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_warwick19/</guid>
      <description>From 17th to 20th of September, right before I graduated my MSc, I had the chance to take part (and help managing, together with other MSc students) the 11th Italian Quantum Information Science Conference (IQIS) organised in Catania. Here I presented the work I had carried out during my Erasmus as part of Lode Pollet&amp;rsquo;s group. At the time I presented a different version of the poster. The one you find here is a &amp;ldquo;more standalone&amp;rdquo; version, that I presented at the Theory of Condensed Matter (TCM) Meeting, held in Warwick.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
