<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>non-Hermitian on Enrico Martello</title>
    <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/tags/non-hermitian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in non-Hermitian on Enrico Martello</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://enricomartello.github.io/tags/non-hermitian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the Adiabatic Non-Hermitian Berry Phase in Feedback-Coupled Oscillators</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/paper_measuring/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/paper_measuring/</guid>
      <description>In this work we verify experimentally that the adiabatic non-Hermitian Berry phase is a purely geometrical effect that leads to significant amplification and damping of the amplitude also for non-cyclical paths within the parameter space even when all eigenenergies are real. We further observe a non-Hermitian analog of the Aharonov&amp;ndash;Bohm solenoid effect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the adiabatic Non-Hermitian Berry Phase in Feedback-Coupled Oscillators</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/unict_seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/unict_seminar/</guid>
      <description>In this talk I presented our most recent work at the University of Catania. It was the first time I ever presented my work!
We measured for the first time the Berry phase in the case of a non-Hermitian Hamiltonian using a mechanical metamaterial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the Adiabatic non-Hermitian Berry Phase in Feedback-Coupled Harmonic Oscillators</title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_warwick22/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_warwick22/</guid>
      <description>For the first time since I began my PhD, I was able to spend more time traveling for conferences. In particular, I presented this poster at the Theory of Condensed Matter (TCM) Meeting, at the University of Warwick, then a few weeks later I took part to the conference on Condensed Matter and Quantum Materials (CMQM) organised by the Institute of Physics (IoP) at the University of Bath, and finally I have presented it at the University of Strathclyde, Glasgow, for the conference on Designing Out of Eequilibrium many-body Quantum systems (DesOEQ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic Mechanical Metamaterials for non-Hermitian Hamiltonians </title>
      <link>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_warwick21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://enricomartello.github.io/publications/poster_warwick21/</guid>
      <description>I presented this poster at the Theory of Condensed Matter (TCM) Meeting, held in Warwick. For more details about this work, take a look at the paper. As it is a large file, it might take some time to download it - be patient :)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
